<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Adventures in Self</title>
        <link>/</link>
        <description>An Unfinished Story</description>
        <generator>Zola</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <item>
            <title>Open Source Initiative: 2021 Platform</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>/journal/2021-osi-platform/</link>
            <guid>/journal/2021-osi-platform/</guid>
            <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is shared on &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;aeva.online&#x2F;journal&#x2F;2021-osi-platform&#x2F;&quot;&gt;my personal site&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and on the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;wiki.opensource.org&#x2F;bin&#x2F;Main&#x2F;OSI%20Board%20of%20Directors&#x2F;Board%20Member%20Elections&#x2F;2021%20Individual%20and%20Affiliate%20Elections&#x2F;Black2021&#x2F;&quot;&gt;2021 OSI Board Elections page&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-me&quot;&gt;About Me&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#about-me&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: about-me&quot;&gt;§&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a software engineer, a buddhist, and a trans and non-binary person. Today,
I work as the Open Source Program Manager for the Azure Confidential Compute
team, for which I engage in technical and community building work in both the
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;confidentialcomputing.io&quot;&gt;Confiential Computing Consortium&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (CCC) and
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cncf.io&quot;&gt;Cloud Native Computing Foundation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (CNCF). I am also a member
of the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;kubernetes&#x2F;community&#x2F;tree&#x2F;master&#x2F;committee-code-of-conduct&quot;&gt;Kubernetes Code of Conduct
Committee&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;,
to which I&#x27;ve brought a framework for Consent Culture and a Restorative
approach to our incident handling procedures. I previously served on the
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.openstack.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;OpenStack&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; Technical Committee, led the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;wiki.openstack.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Ironic&quot;&gt;OpenStack
Ironic&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; project team, participated as a
developer and speaker in the MySQL community for almost a decade, and have
contributed to many other projects, such as Ansible, Matrix, Mixxx, Elastic,
and OpenVZ. I also served as a board member for the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.consent.academy&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Consent
Academy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a Seattle-based 501c(3) non-profit, for
several years. Some of my views on the internal interplay between gender and
buddhism were recently published in
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.goodreads.com&#x2F;book&#x2F;show&#x2F;52531165-transcending&quot;&gt;Transcending&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;views-on-open-source&quot;&gt;Views On Open Source&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#views-on-open-source&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: views-on-open-source&quot;&gt;§&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2021, open source software is used at every company and in many physical
products we rely on, from phones to fridges to cars. As a result, some (mostly
outside this community) now believe that &amp;quot;open source&amp;quot; is a business model (not
true), or a that &amp;quot;open sourcing&amp;quot; something is a one-off event (also not true).
This lexical confusion continues to pose a risk: views not grounded in
experience and an understanding of the legal framework (licensing and
governance) belie the complexity of choices which ultimately shape the
communities of successful open source projects. A proliferation of mismanaged
open source software projects will create unnecessary security and legal risk
for our institutions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To counter this, I believe we need to increase educational outreach with
specific focus towards:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;educating business leaders to empower them with the lexical tools to engage
in nuanced discussions about open source strategy; &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;encouraging lawyers to develop a deeper understanding at the intersection of
data privacy, technology (ab)use, and international copyright;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;engaging in the discussion around open source software supply chain security
as a community issue.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I agree with the objective others have stated in previous years: that the OSI
should be sufficiently funded so this work does not entirely fall on
volunteers. I would like to see outreach to grow the affiliate network continue
so we can support increasing staff dedicated to this mission.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;broader-concerns&quot;&gt;Broader Concerns&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#broader-concerns&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: broader-concerns&quot;&gt;§&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our society is, once again, grappling with the realization that technology is
not neutral: like any tool, software can be used for both good and evil, to
uplift or to oppress. In 2015 I was confronted with this, called on to brief a
foreign military on my open source contributions, it became clear they were
using software I had built in ways I did not support. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I appreciate the debate on ethical source licenses, and believe this comes from
our reflexive care for the impact our work has on society, though I do not
believe licenses are the right tool for this. We need better laws regulating
the civil and military use of certain technologies, and for more lawyers to
become educated in technology and its impact on privacy and civil rights. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the current spotlight on the (ab)uses of Facial Recognition Technology,
which have already resulted in calls to ban FRT &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.banfacialrecognition.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;in the
House&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and in &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.reuters.com&#x2F;article&#x2F;us-washington-tech-idUSKBN21I3AS&quot;&gt;some
states&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, I
believe this will continue to be an important, and emotionally-charged,
conversation, in the years ahead.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-background&quot;&gt;My Background&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#my-background&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: my-background&quot;&gt;§&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2003, before I knew about the OSI or OSD, I had an epiphany as I started my
second job: I could no longer use tools I had built simply because that code
was owned by my former (and already out of business) employer. That epiphany
started me down the open source path, and I quickly came to see how this
approach, if generalized, was more ethical than the alternative: if everyone
could share their tools, we could all build better technolgy (and products)
faster. Automation, the &lt;em&gt;building and sharing&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; of tools so that others may more
quickly create better tools, is &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;aeon.co&#x2F;essays&#x2F;the-offloading-ape-the-human-is-the-beast-that-automates&quot;&gt;one of humanity&#x27;s greatest and most unique
strengths&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
(not my article, but captures my views well). &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early 2010&#x27;s, while building OpenStack, I had the opportunity to work
with several of OSI&#x27;s former board members, who helped me deepen my
understanding of the effect which the OSD had had on my career (unbeknownst to
me before that). I&#x27;ve come to value this framework and the thought and care that
has gone into creating and sustaining it over the years. I would like the 
opportunity to contribute back to the community.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-s-in-a-name&quot;&gt;What&#x27;s In A Name?&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#what-s-in-a-name&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: what-s-in-a-name&quot;&gt;§&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#x27;ve known me for more than the last few years, you would have known me
with a different name: &amp;quot;Devananda&amp;quot; never felt appropriate, only barely
sufficient. The timing of the pandemic and the nature of
open source community interaction means that I haven&#x27;t had the chance to
connect with a lot of old colleagues and friends since changing my name. Humans
are social by nature, and our identities, even our sense of self, is deeply
connected to how our family, friends, and community know us. However, like open
source software projects that sometimes must rebrand themselves, I found that I
needed to change my name, no matter how disruptive it would be.  I mention this
here in the hopes of connecting with folks who may not recognize &amp;quot;Aeva&amp;quot;, but
who would recognize my previous name.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;contact&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#contact&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: contact&quot;&gt;§&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can reach me on &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;aevavoom&quot;&gt;Twitter at @aevavoom&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or by
email at &amp;quot;aeva at aeva dot online&amp;quot;. More ways to contact me can be &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;aeva.online&#x2F;contact&quot;&gt;found
here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>New Site, Who Dis?</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>/journal/2021-newsite/</link>
            <guid>/journal/2021-newsite/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;I thought that migrationg to a static site generator would be a good motivation to spend more time learning Rust ... but once I compiled Rust, and compiled Zola, everything else was just a matter of getting the templating to render well and fiddling with my build-publish workflow. Oh well. I still have a new site that I&#x27;m much happier with :)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and I copied in most, but not quite all, of my previous blog&#x27;s posts.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The build-publish workflow is pretty simple, and this should be much easier to maintain than my last site:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&#x27;Zola&#x27; for the templating engine and site generation, with the &#x27;Zerm&#x27; theme&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I simply edit a Markdown file for each post, maybe add some photos&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;run a shell script which:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invokes &lt;code&gt;zola build&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; to render the static site&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;copies the static site into a docker container for testing&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and copies it into another git repo that only holds the static site&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I test locally using the container, and if I like it, push the static site to GitHub Pages, which renders it at https:&#x2F;&#x2F;aeva.online&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I wanted to migrate off of GitHub Pages, it should be trivial: I could easily run this docker image on a RasPi, for instance, or on any VM.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>identity vectors</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>/journal/2020-identity-vectors/</link>
            <guid>/journal/2020-identity-vectors/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to believe that I’ve been at Microsoft for almost a year now — and that I came down with COVID-19 six and a half months ago. When I look back at the tumultuous political landscape that is 2020, these two events will doubtless color my memories of this year in ways that I can not yet really understand.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Six to Eight Weeks</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>/journal/2020-six-to-eight-weeks/</link>
            <guid>/journal/2020-six-to-eight-weeks/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The doctors told me that it takes six to eight weeks – on average – for healthy folks with my symptoms to recover. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday, April 10th, my work team had our first Virtual Happy Hour, so I was enjoying a little sun in my back yard and a tumbler of Scotch. We’re a relatively new team, and only had a few months to get to know each other before quarantine-in-place orders went into effect in Washington, so the social time together was very welcome.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I woke up Saturday morning, I thought I had a hang-over at first, but by 9am I had a 103F fever. Anxiety was making my heart race — I had been jogging a couple times that week, and had ordered takeout on Monday and Tuesday. Can joggers really spread the ‘rona? Could it be food poisoning from take-out left-overs? Maybe this is something else…&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Tylenol, my fever went down to 101.5. As I spent the day resting, it started getting harder to breathe, and I’m grateful that my phone has a pulse oximeter built in. It didn’t feel like any flu I’ve ever had … my partner Tam was getting worried, so she came over. I remember saying to her that it felt like a Maine Coon curled up on my chest, minus the purring. It was hard to breathe. My hands, feet, and face were tingly, like I was hyper-ventilating, except I wasn’t, and my SpO2 stats were dropping…&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By 4pm, I had a temp of 104.1 – I was still taking Tylenol – and my SpO2 had gone down to 93. Talking made everything worse and I didn’t want to call 911, so Tam started calling around for tele-health options that were open on the weekend. We reached someone. At 7pm, my SpO2 dipped below 90, and the tele-doctor said it was time to go to the Emergency Room.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hallway was completely devoid of life – save for the nurse on a radio behind me, narrating my progress to invisible people.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In hindsight, the strangest thing about the ER visit is that they drew blood and ran a liver&#x2F;kidney panel before they did the nasal swab for COVID-19. At the time, the hardest thing was simply being cold and alone. The staff informed me that they needed to minimize the use of PPE, but also needed to change PPE when leaving the room, and therefore were going to come in to see me as few times as possible — and only one at a time. They gave me the thinnest of blankets. I’m glad I brought my winter coat.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A machine hooked to my right ear monitored my SpO2, but I think it’s real purpose was just to keep me on edge. Every time I relaxed my SpO2 would drop again and trigger more squawking, putting me back on high alert. No one ever came to check on it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After about five hours, a nasal swab, some x-rays, two cups of apple juice, a blood draw, and anxiously trying not to pass out, the attending doctor came in. I could tell because she wore the best PPE and she introduced herself instead of prepping me for another test. My x-rays showed some occlusions and my bloodwork was “ok”. The COVID-19 test came back negative, but she said it was only accurate about 70% of the time, and with the x-ray and all my other symptoms they were confident it was COVID… But, because I didn’t need a ventilator and my kidneys were doing OK, she said I should go home, get lots of rest, and come back if anything got worse.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I finally left, the hallway was completely devoid of life – save for the voice of the nurse on a radio behind me, narrating my progress down the hall to invisible people.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I rested at home for a week — really rested. I didn’t work, because it was too difficult just to sit up for long. I binged on netflix while my housemate brought me food, wearing a mask and bleach-wiping every dish I had touched. After about ten days, I slowly started working again, and by day 14 I felt well enough that I thought I could leave the house. Yes, I checked with my doctor and followed the CDC guidelines. On day 15, I tried to do a little gardening – about 20 minutes of gentle weeding. I collapsed, light-headed and woosy, my ears ringing and my heart pounding, and I needed help getting inside.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I crashed the next day. My fever came back. The inhaler they gave me after the ER wasn’t helping enough any more, so I went in to Swedish’s COVID Respiratory Center, where they gave me two more scripts and a kind-yet-stern talking to for not resting enough. I spent the next few weeks at home, resting, with the hospital staff checking in on me by text message every day and by phone every couple days.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started writing this post around week three. As I finish the post now, the calendar tips into week seven. This was, by all accounts, a “mild” case because I never needed to be on any life-assisting devices. I’ve been sharing status updates on social media in the hopes that, maybe, a few more people will take this seriously, wear a mask, and a few less people get sick.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I shared a summary on Twitter today and it feels appropriate to repost it here –&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 1: ER, very high fevers, bed rest, Rx to help cough&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 2: false recovery, collapsed in yard&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 3: unstable HR, more Rx, bed rest&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 4: bed rest, no fevers, still coughing&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 5: able to sit up at my computer for most of the day!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Week 6: I cooked for myself, and went for an hour-long walk! I’m almost crying with joy and relief&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t believe it’s been 45 days since I went to the ER. It feels like last week and at the same time it feels like a year ago.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m finally getting back a little sense of homeostasis – I cooked dinner last night, and brunch today, and did some baking. Took a drive while it was sunny yesterday. I’m starting to pack, and hopefully moving in a month. Relative to dark times in my past, I’m doing pretty damn well — I was terrified this was going to be like Lyme disease, leaving me with a multi-year recovery, but it seems I’m able to start exercise again.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading, y’all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay safe out there &amp;amp; tell the ones you love how you really feel. This life is too brief not to.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>2019 in Review</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>/journal/2019-in-review/</link>
            <guid>/journal/2019-in-review/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s been two years since I came out. So much has changed. So much has improved.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If 2018 was about &lt;em&gt;accepting&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; that truth, 2019 was about &lt;em&gt;taking action on it&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;..&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For starters, I changed all my online profiles this year. I &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;journal&#x2F;2019-in-review&#x2F;whats-in-a-name.html&quot;&gt;changed my name&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; this year.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realized that my career choices over the past several years had led me uncomfortably far from my ethics. (More on that later…)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result? I spent eight months of 2019 uninsured and underemployed, but still &lt;em&gt;very&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; busy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I interviewed at dozens of tech companies … and only got one offer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I burned through 😱 $30,000 😱 of savings because I kept thinking, &lt;em&gt;surely I’ll land the next interview!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; I would have reorganized my life sooner, had I known I’d be without regular work for a total of 20 months.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I underestimated how much misogyny and transphobia still rule the tech industry.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrestled with an increasing understanding of a contextual, intersectional identity, and adjusted to the embrace of my gender.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yeah, I’m trans, so what?&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; If you don’t like it, please get off this ride right now.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One might say, 2019 was a year of course correction.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m much more involved in things that matter to me now, and also more aware of what I will not compromise on in order to earning a living. Straddling between a day job in the tech industry and a vow I took years ago that I would work to benefit all sentient beings … continues to be a challenge in time and emotional management.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means realigning my financial goals and re-prioritizing my time … but let’s look back at 2019 a little more.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;i-did-a-few-things&quot;&gt;I did a &lt;em&gt;few&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; things!&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#i-did-a-few-things&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: i-did-a-few-things&quot;&gt;§&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;at-defcon-2019.jpeg&quot;
 alt=&quot;Photo of me in a leather hat with a side-pulled hairdo standing in front of a colourful sign that reads: DEFCON&quot;
 style=&quot;float: right;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t all just rumination and navel-gazing… I actually did a few things in 2019!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;started this blog&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;grew tits (heck yeah I’m proud of them!)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;joined a podcast for my first time (that was fun!)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;got a chapter published in a book about the intersection of the buddha-dharma &amp;amp; my experience being trans&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;joined the Kubernetes community &amp;amp; accepted a nomination to their Code of Conduct Committee&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;continued my role as a board member on Seattle’s local sex-positive 501(c)3&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;worked behind the scenes with the QueerCon board to improve their trans inclusivity&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;got a job at Microsoft (ikr? they’ve changed… but still… it’s weird)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spoke at a few conferences
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ML4ALL, one of the best regional conferences I’ve ever been to. I hope it continues!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OpenInfra Summit. I stressed about being back after two years. After &lt;em&gt;transitioning&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SeaGL, local opensource enthusiasts’ group, lotsa greybeards in the rooms&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and IgniteSeattle was perhaps the singularly most pivotal talk experience of my career to date&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in a rare turn of events, I attended several conferences &lt;em&gt;without&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; speaking at them!
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WomenInCloud&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LesbiansWhoTech&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BSidesSF&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DefCon&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KubeCon&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HushCon&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KinkFest&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;oh, and I went on a few camping trips:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;me &amp;amp; a girlfriend in the Utah desert&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;just me in the Cascades – I had intended to do more than one solo offroad trip, but then other things happened&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CriticalNW – it’s like camping, only with 1,500 of my closest friends!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BurningMan – 😂 &amp;amp; 😭 this year as I handled the transfer and purging of all the gear from Camp Potluck. I found the yearbooks we made in 2012, ’13, and ’14, then met up &amp;amp; shared them a few old friends …&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;i-never-feel-like-i-ve-done-enough&quot;&gt;I never feel like I&#x27;ve done enough&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#i-never-feel-like-i-ve-done-enough&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: i-never-feel-like-i-ve-done-enough&quot;&gt;§&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;… until I look back at what I &lt;em&gt;have&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; done.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This helps me to know what I’m capable of, helps me set goals for the next cycle. It helps me overcome imposture syndrome.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, about next year …&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;goals-for-2020&quot;&gt;Goals for 2020&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#goals-for-2020&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: goals-for-2020&quot;&gt;§&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;survive the election cycle – emotional health is key. I’m continuing to reduce my consumption of social media &amp;amp; curate where I’m creating media. be the change you want to see in the world means increasingly relying on decentralized platforms – my blog, mastodon, etc.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rebuild my image &#x2F; brand &#x2F; career – openly transitioning changed everything in ways I’m deeply grateful for, and in ways I’m still learning to see.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;finally get that tattoo I’ve been dreaming of since 2015 😀&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;continue rebuilding my health – more camping trips, more hiking, and more routines&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;write more, on this blog and elsewhere. I’d like to publish a book of my own.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;join more podcasts, and maybe start one. Who wants to join my podcast?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;continue supporting and learning from younger queers in tech&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;attend less, speak more at tech conferences. I can do one a month if I reuse content, less if each talk is brand new.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;follow through on activism that I’ve become engaged with. I see windows of opportunity that could be incredibly impactful &amp;amp; need to keep up my energy to move on them.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;continue building intimate partnerships&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hmm… I didn’t mean for that list to be in any particular order, but apparently I put “relationship” at the bottom and maybe that’s be a bad sign? 🤷&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, that’s all for now! ✨&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you in 2020 &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Transitioning Is an Act of Strength</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>/journal/2019-transitioning-is-strength/</link>
            <guid>/journal/2019-transitioning-is-strength/</guid>
            <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You gave up everything I’ve spent my life fighting for. I can’t imagine how much you must have been hurting inside to choose to do that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;em&gt;Sarah Novotny&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;life-changes&quot;&gt;Life, Changes&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#life-changes&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: life-changes&quot;&gt;§&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, I was having dinner with Sarah at one of our old haunts — it’s been four years since she moved away from Seattle, and the same Ethiopian restaurant is still here, still serving up the same delicious dinners on platters of Teff Injera. Somehow, it seems longer than four years. So much has changed in that time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve both built our careers around open source, and I have respected and admired her tenacity and her compassion for as long as I’ve known her. Sarah is several years my senior in the community, with considerably more reputation and public visibility, and yet in the past decade we’ve both moved through roles as project leads and VPs, sharing stories along the way.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;city-mouse-or-country-mouse&quot;&gt;City Mouse or Country Mouse?&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#city-mouse-or-country-mouse&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: city-mouse-or-country-mouse&quot;&gt;§&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;sunset-downtown.jpeg&quot;
 alt=&quot;a beautiful picture I took of sunset over Puget Sound from my Downtown apartment in 2015&quot;
 style=&quot;float: right;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As dinner went on, conversation turned to housing, to dreams of future plans.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just after she moved away, I lived for a year in a beautiful downtown penthouse with a water view over the ferry docks, and the farmer’s market just three blocks away… Living there taught me how much my sleep cycle and mental health benefit from being connected to the sunset, and how much I enjoy an urban lifestyle that’s hard to find in the US. I’d like to find that again.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also want to have land in the countryside again. I used to have five acres, but gave it up in a divorce; I think twenty acres would be good — enough space for friends, some chickens, dogs, and farms to grow our own food. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who wants to start a queer commune with me?&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we talked about rebuilding our lives, the ongoing process of figuring out who we are in light of physical changes. We’ve each given Ignite Talks about what a changing identity means at the intersection of technology, public perception, and personal change.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;is-perception-identity&quot;&gt;Is Perception == Identity?&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#is-perception-identity&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: is-perception-identity&quot;&gt;§&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I say &lt;em&gt;I came out as trans&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; because I wasn’t willing to give up my social and professional network, so the only option was to ask everyone to change their perception of my identity. I wasn’t willing to sever ties with my coding history even as I changed my name and online handles, though I’m still struggling with this. Everyone’s journey is radically unique, and I learned that there’s no playbook for transitioning as a mid-career professional in open source. My reputation is a valuable assets built over fifteen years, with ties to a global &amp;amp; multicultural community. That reputation, it’s part of my identity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;me&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; that my network knew &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wasn’t me any more&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, and that left only one option: accept the risks that come from telling everyone.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;a-coming-out-plan&quot;&gt;A Coming Out Plan&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#a-coming-out-plan&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: a-coming-out-plan&quot;&gt;§&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why don&#x27;t you just dress like a guy for the interview?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;em&gt;well-meaning male colleague&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I began this gender-journey with a vague plan — I couldn’t transition within the VP role that I had in 2017, so I left.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took six months off work before starting a role as Staff Researcher in the Samsung Open Source Group. I had a supportive manager, and would be paid well to work from home and guide their open source cloud contributions. This should have set me up for several years – enough time for my plan – but circumstances unrelated to me ended that very suddenly ….&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By this time, I’d had a year of HRT and donated most of my pre-transition clothes. I call this time the Uncanny Valley. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-uncanny-gender-valley&quot;&gt;The Uncanny (Gender) Valley&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#the-uncanny-gender-valley&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: the-uncanny-gender-valley&quot;&gt;§&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;uncanny_valley.jpeg&quot;
 alt=&quot;graph of the uncanny valley of human-to-machine likeness&quot;
 style=&quot;float: right;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interviewing in 2019 was a nightmare – my resume and my reputation got me dozens of in-person interviews for roles as a director, or as a principal &#x2F; staff engineer… and even though I’d held roles at that level for the past five years, no one would make an offer! Almost every interviewer was a man in their late 40’s, and they were all suddenly, &lt;em&gt;visibly&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, uncomfortable around me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hearing of my struggles, a few well-meaning male colleagues suggested that I just dress like a guy for interviews….&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ouch&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They didn’t know how much that hurt.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;my-gender-is-not-armor-any-more&quot;&gt;My Gender Is Not Armor Any More&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#my-gender-is-not-armor-any-more&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: my-gender-is-not-armor-any-more&quot;&gt;§&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So after almost a year without health insurance and two years without steady income, my transition plan was a wreck in the rear-view mirror. I had a dwindling savings account and a shrinking network, and I settled for the first tangible offer I got. It’s the same career level I held in 2012, &lt;em&gt;but it’ll pay the rent and the doctor’s bills&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know what’s more important than my career?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I’m happy in my own body for the first time in 20 years.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know what I want back?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My career.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;strength-in-vulnerability&quot;&gt;Strength In Vulnerability&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#strength-in-vulnerability&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: strength-in-vulnerability&quot;&gt;§&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I had finished sharing my story with Sarah, she shook her head and, with all the kindness in the world, said words I’ll never forget:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You gave up everything I’ve spent my life fighting for. I can’t imagine how much you must have been hurting inside to choose to do that.” &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yeah. You get it.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve learned through experience how much our identity is defined by others, how &lt;em&gt;who we are&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; exists in relation to &lt;em&gt;how we’re perceived&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, and how painful it is to live with the cognitive dissonance of an identity that looks nothing like one’s sense of self.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not wearing armor to hide any more.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And it feels so good to be seen.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Job Hunt Is Over</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>/journal/2019-job-hunt-is-over/</link>
            <guid>/journal/2019-job-hunt-is-over/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a month now since I signed an employment contract with Microsoft.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You read that correctly — the giant tech company which I swore, back in the 90’s, I would never work for. Even though most of my colleagues have been very encouraging, even reminding me that Microsoft isn’t as monopolistic or walled-off as it once was, there are still some things which bear clarification (especially for any readers that have known me during the OpenStack or MySQL days).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off, no, I’m not leaving open source. I believe that &lt;em&gt;humanity’s growth accelerates by sharing our tools&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. For any business, it is important to delineate which software provides specific &amp;amp; unique value, and then to weigh the cost of privately maintaining those tools vs. the cost of participating in shared development of those tools. In my experience, it’s almost always better to share the tools.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I look forward to bringing this view with me to work every day, and (as far as I can tell) my current employer appreciates this view more than many other companies I’ve worked for in the past.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the end of 2016, I haven’t been active in any particular upstream community. Between trying to run an OpenStack-based cloud hosting company, the end of that position, &lt;em&gt;coming out as trans&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, and my dreadful job hunt ever since (which I &lt;em&gt;rarely talk about&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) … I haven’t had the funding to travel to a lot of conferences that I used to.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am exceedingly grateful to travel support programs and generous friends that gave me places to crash so I could get to #LesbiansWhoTech, #ML4ALL, #OpenStackSummit, and #DEFCON this year. And it was delightful to see friends when I made it out to OpenStack Denver, even if I’m not an active contributor any longer. &amp;lt;3’s to you all!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this time, my focus has shifted away from “do F&#x2F;OSS for F&#x2F;OSS’s sake” to accommodate a more nuanced view of the impact we – software developers – have. I spent a lot of time reflecting on how ML&#x2F;AI is reshaping our society, and on how cloud technology already has.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen OpenStack Ironic used in places that I would never have wanted my creations to be: surveillance industries and even a foreign military.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have the incredible satisfaction of knowing some amazing scientific research powered by that same code: Ironic is enabling scientists to study particle collisions and work on cancer cures.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So anyway… my attention has shifted towards social and societal issues: trans rights, surveillance capitalism, digital freedoms, the right of all humans to self-determination and self-expression. I’m trying to catch up and learning a lot from others’ research in this area, and have begun giving talks on the impact of Machine Learning. I also hold a seat on the board of a non-profit that teaches about consent culture, and I was just elected to a seat on the Kubernetes Code of Conduct Committee.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being paid specifically to build open source software is just one way I can work to make the world more open and inclusive. Having enough money and time that I can support causes is another path, as is advocating for change from within a large organization.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2020 is going to see me doing all three of these…&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wish me luck!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Gender Markers</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>/journal/2019-gender-markers/</link>
            <guid>/journal/2019-gender-markers/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(content warning: gender issues and gender-based violence, no specifics but still may be difficult for some)&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, the Washington State Department of Licensing held a public hearing for comments on the proposed legislation to add an ‘X’ gender marker option on state-issued ID’s. I chose to go and stand up for all the non-binary, intersex, and transgender members of my communities.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was blown away by the stories that I heard, and, to be honest, a little surprised that not a single nay-sayer chose to speak up. At the very end a 16-year old high school student, who hadn’t planned to speak, bravely chose to stand up and tell their story …&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made it through all the other testimonies without tears, but to see a student facing the same struggle that I did as a teenager and having the language to understand it, support from adults, and the courage to speak out … Well, that student reminded me why I’m adding my voice to the chorus of change. I’m grateful for that reminder. I won’t forget it for a long time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m also very grateful for the friends there to hold my hand while I cried, remembering the verbal and physical assaults I faced at that age – just for being different in ways that I had no context to understand.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of those friends recorded my testimony, which I’ve uploaded below. Transcription follows. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BROKEN LINK -- https:&#x2F;&#x2F;aeva.online&#x2F;wp-content&#x2F;uploads&#x2F;2019&#x2F;08&#x2F;Dol-gender-x-testimony.mp4&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#191919;&quot;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;I identified as other than the gender assigned at birth since I was
very young, and faced discrimination, both when I was younger and as an
adult, for that.

In that time, I’ve held senior and executive positions in the tech
industry. I’ve seen how a lack of representation, of identification,
even in the &amp;lt;hand wave&amp;gt; shining example of the tech industry. It’s
affected friends. It’s affected peers. And it’s affected me.

As others have said, it also affects our ability to travel. I used to
travel a lot for work [and] I’ve been questioned and challenged at the
border because that border agent didn’t think I matched the gender
marker on my documentation. I know that affects colleagues of mine.

There’s one more aspect of this that is not particular to the tech
industry, but rather affects all of industry.

Because I hid that part of my identity at work for a while, I’ve seen
how the fear of disclosure affects people. Imagine, if you will, being
intersex or non-binary, knowing that the marker on your identification
doesn’t match how you look or how you are, and the fear of that being
disclosed to your employer without any legal protection. That
potential, that fear affects people. It puts their jobs at risk, and it
puts our companies at risk.

I unambiguously support this measure so that legal documentation in our
state accurately represents the people that work in our state. This
will reduce the stigma and reduce discrimination for intersex and
non-binary people.

Thank you.
&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Rebuilding my miniserver</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>/journal/2019-rebuilding-my-miniserver/</link>
            <guid>/journal/2019-rebuilding-my-miniserver/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;CONTENT MISSING&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>What&#x27;s in a Name?</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>/journal/2019-whats-in-a-name/</link>
            <guid>/journal/2019-whats-in-a-name/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;A MAN IN A frock held up his right hand and said a few words, and I got to fill out some paperwork. It is strange that this process makes me feel better about myself. I abhor paperwork.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rites of Passage&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; have been sociologically and psychologically important to humans for, well, as long as recorded history. As someone who grew up without cultural roots (or rather, with roots in several different major world cultures) and never identified with any specific culture, I’ve often been a little jealous of folks who get to have a bar&#x2F;batmitzva, a big ol’ denominational wedding, or the like. I never had those. Heck, I didn’t even have a graduation ceremony!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So a few years ago I started &lt;em&gt;making my own sacred rites&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, celebrating the milestones of life in my own way. Fuck society and fuck your burn — by which I mean, &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;you should make your own rules, too.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2017, I threw myself an &lt;em&gt;unwedding&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; (complete with a tiered cake) to mark the end of one era of my life and celebrate the formation of so many new connections to my chosen family.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2017 was also the year I started to come out. To present. &lt;em&gt;To be present&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder how I’ll look back on this day and celebrate it next year….&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>What Happened To OpenStack</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>/journal/2019-what-happened-openstack/</link>
            <guid>/journal/2019-what-happened-openstack/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The project is still quite healthy and is following the usual hype curve: OpenStack is finally mature enough that it’s less interesting to talk about, so it’s understandable that people think &lt;em&gt;something&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; happened.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The folks asking me this question are generally curios and good intentioned, and I think my answer says a lot about my professional background, so even during an interview I indulge in a short ramble.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know, I know … I should have written about it at the time, but I had other things going on and wasn’t making space in my life to write. So I’ve decided to revisit the topic today. Next time someone asks me, I’ll just point them here 😉&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all knew that, for the long-term success of the OpenStack ecosystem, we needed a hyper-scale OpenStack public cloud to succeed, and a healthy set of SaaS applications to be built upon the IaaS&#x2F;PaaS layers that we had. We knew there needed to be at more than one hyperscale implementation to avoid a gravity problem (in the early days, that was RackSpace).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Publicly, lots of folks were talking about this; common headlines compared &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;blogs.forrester.com&#x2F;press-newsroom&#x2F;openstack-is-positioned-to-become-one-of-five-public-cloud-camps&#x2F;&quot;&gt;OpenStack to AWS&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and every VC and analyst &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;superuser.openstack.org&#x2F;articles&#x2F;forrester-says-ready-set-openstack&#x2F;&quot;&gt;wanted to know&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.zdnet.com&#x2F;article&#x2F;getting-openstack-ready-for-the-enterprise&#x2F;&quot;&gt;if it was ready&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;redhatstackblog.redhat.com&#x2F;2014&#x2F;11&#x2F;10&#x2F;openstack-2015-the-year-of-the-enterprise&#x2F;&quot;&gt;the Enterprise&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.mirantis.com&#x2F;blog&#x2F;ask-whether-openstack-ready-enterprise&#x2F;&quot;&gt;yet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I even &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;KX1AQCJrhQs&quot;&gt;sat on a panel to discuss this&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; very question! &lt;em&gt;(edit: updated with link)&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But over time, this key component of our success never materialized. Why was that?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in 2014 I was working at HP Cloud. Money was pouring into OpenStack and we were all riding high on that. This was the year that OpenStack hype peaked, and I will never forget the Carnival at the Paris Summit. &lt;em&gt;Tre magnifique!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; From outside, however, it may not have been obvious that this was coming from Telcos and Hardware Vendors seeking to influence the direction of OpenStack. Specifically, these companies wanted to create the technological basis for integrated private cloud solutions they could take to market quickly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Privately, we could see that these market forces were opposed to actually achieving hyperscale. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.openstack.org&#x2F;project-team-guide&#x2F;introduction.html#the-project-structure-reform-a-k-a-the-big-tent&quot;&gt;The Big Tent&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; was a bold move to try and address some of these issues. We (that is, the Technical Committee) did what we could, but in the end we couldn’t fix the problem because we didn’t control the purse strings.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see, almost every company contributing substantially to OpenStack at that time relied on &lt;em&gt;Enterprise customers&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. That’s a nice way of saying well-known brands who spend a lot of money on each other every year. Unlike the hyper-scalers, Enterprise customers generally do not have an interest in building their own servers or writing their own switch firmware. They buy these things (and the support contracts for them) from other Enterprise companies that make them, and &lt;em&gt;those&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; companies want to keep making money from these deals.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, distros and operators struggled to make OpenStack installable so that they could roll out deployments to satisfy the market demand. And the Enterprise demand for new private cloud regions was &lt;em&gt;incredibly&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; high! A lot of internal pressure was being put on the OpenStack developer teams (at the Distros, Telco’s, HW vendors) to create software that worked well at a scale these Enterprise Customers needed, roughly in the 1,000’s to 10,000’s of cores with a small number of regions for geographic resiliency.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, building a distributed system for a scale of 10,000 cores is fundamentally different than building for 10,000,000 cores. Besides just changing the code, scaling up by another three orders of magnitude requires fundamental changes in how any business operate. The margins would need to become much, much smaller. Gone would be the 3rd party support contracts, the B2B deals, the value-added software – the grease in the sales’ teams wheels. The enterprise hardware &amp;amp; software giants were not willing to restructure their businesses that much, and the organic growth of companies &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ovh.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;like OVH&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; was too slow (even though I think they are still on the right track).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating a viable, open source, hyperscale cloud software solution was &lt;strong&gt;against the best interest&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; of the companies most heavily investing in OpenStack’s development.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my usual fashion, I tried to draw this on a napkin one day. The original is long since lost, so I’ve redrawn it from memory below.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;openstack-influence-chart.png&quot;
 alt=&quot;a black and white drawing that reads: telcos to hardware vendors to distros to operators to application developers, with a subtext indicating greatest influence on the side of telcos and least influence on the side of application developers&quot;
 &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Influence was flowing from the wrong direction. Product management within the Telco, Hardware, and Distro space — that is, companies like ATT, Cisco, Dell, and RedHat — were pouring in money to pay developers to have influence and write code, funding lavish parties and inflating salaries (in full disclosure, I certainly enjoyed the parties, and while I got paid well, I didn’t make out nearly as well as a lot of folks did). Meanwhile, Operators were getting further and further behind the release-train, had little voice (they were busy operating the clouds, after all) … and the end-users of the cloud (app developers) had almost no voice at all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, revenues would need to come from the growth of supported businesses on top of the cloud (ie, app developers’ success), but we couldn’t get there because operators weren’t able to scale up enough, or maintain cross-cloud compatibility well enough, for a healthy market to flourish on top of the cloud. Everyone on the left-hand side of that diagram was too busy trying to differentiate to win deals against each other.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this going on, the upstream technical team leads — who could see the problem — were lobbying inside our respective companies to change the priorities. We convinced some managers and executives to get onboard with tactical investments in code and infrastructure, but we couldn’t get enough backing for the larger changes that were needed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As long as the financial influencers were focused on the business models of mid-sized customers (MSP’s and Enterprise markets), they were not willing to invest in the massive strategic efforts needed to make OpenStack competitive in the hyperscale market. The vast majority of developers, whose project goals were dictated by PMs and executives within their employers, were thus busy driving features (designed to take advantage of “value-added integrations”, the grease of the Enterprise sales cycle) into the codebase, and no one could fix the core issues that had become apparent to all the deployers who were busily trying to scale up their clouds.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see, the successful hyperscalers had already removed middleware marginal cost. Google, AWS, even Facebook, all make their own servers, switches, storage, etc. They fork open source projects then pay developers to maintain and improve private versions so that they can stay ahead (some projects are now &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theregister.co.uk&#x2F;2018&#x2F;10&#x2F;16&#x2F;mongodb_licensning_change&#x2F;&quot;&gt;trying to prevent this&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;). These companies pioneered scale by shaving the costs off their infrastructure, but those efficiencies have not made it back to the Enterprise market. They became the behemoths they are, in no small part, by building processes, teams, and hardware to break any reliance on 3rd parties for software, hardware, or support.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, you see, creating a viable, open source, hyperscale cloud software solution was against the best interest of the companies most heavily investing in OpenStack’s development.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you’re looking at other cloud products, think about similar conflicts of interest that might be affecting your favorite spokespersons today… (&lt;em&gt;I’m looking at you, kubernetes&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those of us who joined OpenStack early and dreamed big, well, we had no chance of building those dreams within OpenStack. It became something less hype-worthy but perhaps even more useful: &lt;strong&gt;an extensible tool for mid-scale infrastructure automation, powering thousands of businesses around the world, including many non-profit and public-good institutions&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And – just to be clear – I’m very glad to have been able to help in my small way to build a tool that has been used so widely for good.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am publishing this now in the hope that it can serve as a warning to everyone out there who is investing in Kubernetes. You’ll never be able to run it as effectively, at the same scale, as GKE does – unless you also invest in a holistic change to your organization.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even then, if you’re using Kubernetes, you probably won’t succeed, because it isn’t in Google’s best interest to let anyone else actually compete with GKE.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that’s probably OK. In fact, OpenStack + Kubernetes is probably just fine for what ever you’re building, and neither project is going anywhere any time soon.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If another company wants to stand a chance in the hyperscale space, it will need to look holistically at its entire business apparatus, and either repeat the Google&#x2F;Facebook&#x2F;Amazon model of privatizing open source and investing in your own server fabrication &lt;em&gt;or band together with other vertically-focused, open source businesses in order to compete.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do that, please drop me a line.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d love to help.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Hi, I&#x27;m queer and trans</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>/journal/2019-hi-queer-trans/</link>
            <guid>/journal/2019-hi-queer-trans/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s something I need to get off my chest.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve used a lot of different labels to describe myself over the years – geek, goth, autodidact, polyglot, kinkster, polyamorous, third-culture kid, dharma bum, database admin, software developer, cloud architect, VP. None feel as risky to claim as #trans, and yet, none of those other labels are as authentic, none require as much vulnerability to share.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on my childhood reveals a difficult truth: when I was in primary school, I was one of the girls. Everyone (except me) knew it, but in a small southern California town in 1992, none of us had the social vocabulary to talk about gender fluidity, least of all me. By the time I turned 16, I had figured out how to pass as though I was over 21, and very clearly “a man”, because this made it much safer to exist in public.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In essence, to survive childhood, I traded the freedom to express myself authentically for a thinly-constructed sense of safety, and I’ve been paying an internal cost for that choice ever since. My close friends have all known … to some degree or another. I’ve always done little things to honor my feminine side, even as my career took off and I became modestly well known in Open Source as a guy. That exposure, that network, helped me learn a lot about who I am and connect with an amazingly beautiful &amp;amp; diverse network of people.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I’m done holding back who I am.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday’s #WomenInTech Summit was incredible for a lot of reasons, and it was the firs second time that I’ve been at an event with my F&#x2F;OSS community since openly starting this transition. Most notable for me was the message (carried by several speakers) that we women bring a power, an opportunity, to tech companies through our ability to share our authentic, vulnerable selves. That strength isn’t unique to women.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;em&gt;it is the only way forward for me.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; I know that I won’t be able to succeed in my next professional endeavor unless I embrace this truth.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, hi there, internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m a queer trans woman in tech.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
