<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Adventures in Self</title>
        <link>/</link>
        <description>An Unfinished Story</description>
        <generator>Zola</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <atom:link href="/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <item>
            <title>Answers to Luis Villa&#x27;s Four Questions</title>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>/journal/2021-osi-four-questions/</link>
            <guid>/journal/2021-osi-four-questions/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Luis Villa &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;opensource.com&#x2F;article&#x2F;21&#x2F;3&#x2F;board-elections-osi&quot;&gt;posted a series of questions on opensource.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for this year&#x27;s OSI Board Nominees to answer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post, I share my thoughts.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Open Source Initiative: 2021 Platform</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>/journal/2021-osi-platform/</link>
            <guid>/journal/2021-osi-platform/</guid>
            <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my official announcement post for my candidacy for the OSI Board of Directors in 2021. Read on for the description of my platform and goals.
This post is shared on &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;aeva.online&#x2F;journal&#x2F;2021-osi-platform&#x2F;&quot;&gt;my personal site&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and on the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;wiki.opensource.org&#x2F;bin&#x2F;Main&#x2F;OSI%20Board%20of%20Directors&#x2F;Board%20Member%20Elections&#x2F;2021%20Individual%20and%20Affiliate%20Elections&#x2F;Black2021&#x2F;&quot;&gt;2021 OSI Board Elections page&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>An overdue reflection on 2020</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>/journal/2021-reflecting-on-2020/</link>
            <guid>/journal/2021-reflecting-on-2020/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;I try to journal around New Years every year. I&#x27;m running late this year, but with good reason - I had top surgery in December and wasn&#x27;t able to sit at my desk and comfortably write for a few weeks. By the time I could, I was swamped at work and focusing on that. Check back for a follow-up to this post when I get around to actually writing it 😅&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>New Site, Who Dis?</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>/journal/2021-newsite/</link>
            <guid>/journal/2021-newsite/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;I thought that migrationg to a static site generator would be a good motivation to spend more time learning Rust ... but once I compiled Rust, and compiled Zola, everything else was just a matter of getting the templating to render well and fiddling with my build-publish workflow. Oh well. I still have a new site that I&#x27;m much happier with :)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Identity Vectors</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>/journal/2020-identity-vectors/</link>
            <guid>/journal/2020-identity-vectors/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to believe that I’ve been at Microsoft for almost a year now — and that I came down with COVID-19 six and a half months ago. When I look back at the tumultuous political landscape that is 2020, these two events will doubtless color my memories of this year in ways that I can not yet really understand.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Six to Eight Weeks</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>/journal/2020-six-to-eight-weeks/</link>
            <guid>/journal/2020-six-to-eight-weeks/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The doctors told me that it takes six to eight weeks – on average – for healthy folks with my symptoms to recover. It took more than six months.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Transitioning Is an Act of Strength</title>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>/journal/2019-transitioning-is-strength/</link>
            <guid>/journal/2019-transitioning-is-strength/</guid>
            <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You gave up everything I’ve spent my life fighting for.
I can’t imagine how much you must have been hurting inside to choose to do that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sarah Novotny&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;life-changes&quot;&gt;Life, Changes&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#life-changes&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: life-changes&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, I was having dinner with Sarah at one of our old haunts — it’s been four years since she moved away from Seattle, and the same Ethiopian restaurant is still here, still serving up the same delicious dinners on platters of Teff Injera. Somehow, it seems longer than four years. So much has changed in that time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve both built our careers around open source, and I have respected and admired her tenacity and her compassion for as long as I’ve known her. Sarah is several years my senior in the community, with considerably more reputation and public visibility, and yet in the past decade we’ve both moved through roles as project leads and VPs, sharing stories along the way.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;city-mouse-or-country-mouse&quot;&gt;City Mouse or Country Mouse?&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#city-mouse-or-country-mouse&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: city-mouse-or-country-mouse&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;sunset-downtown.jpeg&quot;
 alt=&quot;a beautiful picture I took of sunset over Puget Sound from my Downtown apartment in 2015&quot;
 style=&quot;float: right;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As dinner went on, conversation turned to housing, to dreams of future plans.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just after she moved away, I lived for a year in a beautiful downtown penthouse with a water view over the ferry docks, and the farmer’s market just three blocks away… Living there taught me how much my sleep cycle and mental health benefit from being connected to the sunset, and how much I enjoy an urban lifestyle that’s hard to find in the US. I’d like to find that again.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also want to have land in the countryside again. I used to have five acres, but gave it up in a divorce; I think twenty acres would be good — enough space for friends, some chickens, dogs, and farms to grow our own food. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we talked about rebuilding our lives, the ongoing process of figuring out who we are in light of physical changes. We’ve each given Ignite Talks about what a changing identity means at the intersection of technology, public perception, and personal change.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;is-perception-identity&quot;&gt;Is Perception == Identity?&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#is-perception-identity&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: is-perception-identity&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I say &lt;em&gt;I came out as trans&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; because I wasn’t willing to give up my social and professional network, so the only option was to ask everyone to change their perception of my identity. I wasn’t willing to sever ties with my coding history even as I changed my name and online handles, though I’m still struggling with this. Everyone’s journey is radically unique, and I learned that there’s no playbook for transitioning as a mid-career professional in open source. My reputation is a valuable assets built over fifteen years, with ties to a global &amp;amp; multicultural community. That reputation, it’s part of my identity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;me&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; that my network knew &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wasn’t me any more&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, and that left only one option: accept the risks that come from telling everyone.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;a-coming-out-plan&quot;&gt;A Coming Out Plan&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#a-coming-out-plan&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: a-coming-out-plan&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why don&#x27;t you just dress like a guy for the interview?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;well-meaning male colleague&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I began this gender-journey with a vague plan — I couldn’t transition within the VP role that I had in 2017, so I left.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took six months off work before starting a role as Staff Researcher in the Samsung Open Source Group. I had a supportive manager, and would be paid well to work from home and guide their open source cloud contributions. This should have set me up for several years – enough time for my plan – but circumstances unrelated to me ended that very suddenly ….&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By this time, I’d had a year of HRT and donated most of my pre-transition clothes. I call this time the Uncanny Valley. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-uncanny-gender-valley&quot;&gt;The Uncanny (Gender) Valley&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#the-uncanny-gender-valley&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: the-uncanny-gender-valley&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;uncanny_valley.jpeg&quot;
 alt=&quot;graph of the uncanny valley of human-to-machine likeness&quot;
 style=&quot;float: right;&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interviewing in 2019 was a nightmare – my resume and my reputation got me dozens of in-person interviews for roles as a director, or as a principal &#x2F; staff engineer… and even though I’d held roles at that level for the past five years, no one would make an offer! Almost every interviewer was a man in their late 40’s, and they were all suddenly, &lt;em&gt;visibly&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, uncomfortable around me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hearing of my struggles, a few well-meaning male colleagues suggested that I just dress like a guy for interviews….&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ouch&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They didn’t know how much that hurt.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;my-gender-is-not-armor-any-more&quot;&gt;My Gender Is Not Armor Any More&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#my-gender-is-not-armor-any-more&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: my-gender-is-not-armor-any-more&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So after almost a year without health insurance and two years without steady income, my transition plan was a wreck in the rear-view mirror. I had a dwindling savings account and a shrinking network, and I settled for the first tangible offer I got. It’s the same career level I held in 2012 -- but it will pay the rent and the doctor’s bills.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know what’s more important than my career?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happiness, and I’m happy in my own body for the first time in 20 years.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know what I want back?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My career.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;strength-in-vulnerability&quot;&gt;Strength In Vulnerability&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#strength-in-vulnerability&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: strength-in-vulnerability&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I had finished sharing my story with Sarah, she shook her head and, with all the kindness in the world, said words I’ll never forget: &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;You gave up everything I’ve spent my life fighting for. I can’t imagine how much you must have been hurting inside to choose to do that.&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Yeah, you get it,&amp;quot; I thought.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve learned through experience how much our identity is defined by others, how &lt;em&gt;who we are&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; exists in relation to &lt;em&gt;how we’re perceived&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, and how painful it is to live with the cognitive dissonance of an identity that looks nothing like one’s sense of self.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not wearing armor to hide any more.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it feels so good to be seen.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The Job Hunt Is Over</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>/journal/2019-job-hunt-is-over/</link>
            <guid>/journal/2019-job-hunt-is-over/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a month now since I signed an employment contract with Microsoft.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You read that correctly — the giant tech company which I swore, back in the 90’s, I would never work for. Even though most of my colleagues have been very encouraging, even reminding me that Microsoft isn’t as monopolistic or walled-off as it once was, there are still some things which bear clarification (especially for any readers that have known me during the OpenStack or MySQL days).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Gender Markers</title>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>/journal/2019-gender-markers/</link>
            <guid>/journal/2019-gender-markers/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(content warning: gender issues and gender-based violence, no specifics but still may be difficult for some)&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, the Washington State Department of Licensing held a public hearing for comments on the proposed legislation to add an ‘X’ gender marker option on state-issued ID’s. I chose to go and stand up for all the non-binary, intersex, and transgender members of my communities.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Rebuilding my miniserver</title>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>/journal/2019-rebuilding-my-miniserver/</link>
            <guid>/journal/2019-rebuilding-my-miniserver/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;CONTENT MISSING&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>What&#x27;s in a Name?</title>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>/journal/2019-whats-in-a-name/</link>
            <guid>/journal/2019-whats-in-a-name/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;A MAN IN A frock held up his right hand and said a few words, and I got to fill out some paperwork. It is strange that this process makes me feel better about myself. I abhor paperwork.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>What Happened To OpenStack</title>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>/journal/2019-what-happened-openstack/</link>
            <guid>/journal/2019-what-happened-openstack/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;The project is still quite healthy and is following the usual hype curve: OpenStack is finally mature enough that it’s less interesting to talk about, so it’s understandable that people think &lt;em&gt;something&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; happened.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The folks asking me this question are generally curios and good intentioned, and I think my answer says a lot about my professional background, so even during an interview I indulge in a short ramble.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know, I know … I should have written about it at the time, but I had other things going on and wasn’t making space in my life to write. So I’ve decided to revisit the topic today. Next time someone asks me, I’ll just point them here 😉&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Hi, I&#x27;m queer and trans</title>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <link>/journal/2019-hi-queer-trans/</link>
            <guid>/journal/2019-hi-queer-trans/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s something I need to get off my chest.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve used a lot of different labels to describe myself over the years – geek, goth, autodidact, polyglot, kinkster, polyamorous, third-culture kid, dharma bum, database admin, software developer, cloud architect, VP. None feel as risky to claim as #trans, and yet, none of those other labels are as authentic, none require as much vulnerability to share.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
